UNITY DEVELOPER

JOÃO BATISTA FORTUNATO JUNIOR Sorocaba-SP, Brazil +55 (15) 99788-6485 joao.fortunatojr@hotmail.com

ABOUT

Passionate about games and Unity developer working professionally for over 5 years. I have experience in the development of games and gamified solutions for Android and iOS, as well in augmented reality projects (using Vuforia and AR Foundation) and virtual reality (Oculus Quest and HTC Vive).

SKILLS

- C#
- Unity
- VR
- AR

- Git
- SOLID
- Android
- iOS
- PlayFab

- HTML, JavaScript
- Scrum
- SQL
- Firebase

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Luby Software

Tech Lead / Unity Developer

Sorocaba-SP, Brazil May 2023-present

I work on the development of Unity projects such as casual games (PC, Android, iOS and WebGl), virtual reality, augmented reality and development tools. As a Tech Lead, I help other developers with the projects they are working on, perform Code Reviews, participate in meetings to answer technical questions from both our team and clients, help with the preparation of budgets and project deadline estimates, hold meetings with the team to define development standards, both in code and in Unity.

LIGA Facens

Tech Lead / Unity Developer

Sorocaba-SP, Brazil May 2018-May 2023

During my time at LIGA, I worked on various types of solutions using the Unity engine as virtual reality trainings for companies such as ZF (ZF Friedrichshafen AG), ABB (ABBN: SIX Swiss Ex), Case IH, DPR, among others. I also worked on mobile games (Android & iOS) most of them for the brazilian television company SBT. As in LIGA, the demand for projects is very high, I gained a lot of experience in developing projects quickly, but always trying to maintain quality, focusing on maintaining a good performance on the hardware on which the applications run and learning new concepts and technologies that facilitate the development process. As Unity Tech Lead, I am responsible not only for the development process, but also for instructing and helping less experienced developers, most of them students, clearing their doubts, performing code reviews and holding meetings to bring new technologies and solutions made with Unity.

EDUCATION

- Graduate in Software Engineering (Facens 2020-2022)
- Associate Degree in Digital Games (Facens 2016-2018)
- Certificate in IT (ETEC Fernando Prestes 2014-2015)

LANGUAGES

English: AdvancedPortuguese: Native

EXTRA ACTIVITIES

- LIGA Game Jam 2016
- LIGA Game Jam 2017
- LIGA Game Jam 2017
- Global Game Jam 2018
- Good Game Brazil Jam 2022
- Farmando XP Game Jam 2023

PORTIFOLIO

https://jfortunatojr.com